How can one person enjoy good health, while another person looks old before her time?
为什么有的人身体健康，有的人却显得未老先衰？
Humans have been asking this question for thousands of years, and recently, it’s becoming clearer and clearer to scientists that the differences between people’s rates of aging lie in the complex interactions among genes, social relationships, environments and lifestyles.
数千年来，人类一直在问这个问题；而最近，科学家们越来越清楚地认识到，人与人衰老速度的差异，在于基因、社会关系、环境和生活方式之间复杂的相互作用。
Even though you were born with a particular set of genes, the way you live can influence how they express themselves.
尽管你生来就带有一套特定的基因，但你怎样生活，能够影响这些基因如何表达。
Some lifestyle factors may even turn genes on or shut them off.
某些生活方式因素甚至可能开启或关闭基因。
Deep within the genetic heart of all our cells are telomeres, or repeating segments of noncoding DNA that live at the ends of the chromosomes.
我们所有细胞的遗传核心深处都有端粒，也就是位于染色体末端、由非编码DNA构成的重复片段。
They form caps at the ends of the chromosomes and keep the genetic material together.
它们在染色体末端形成帽状结构，把遗传物质维系在一起。
Shortening with each cell division, they help determine how fast a cell ages.
它们随着每一次细胞分裂而缩短，参与决定细胞衰老的快慢。
When they become too short, the cell stops dividing altogether.
端粒变得太短时，细胞就会完全停止分裂。
This isn’t the only reason a cell can age—there are other stresses on cells we don’t yet understand very well—but short telomeres are one of the major reasons human cells grow old.
这并不是细胞会衰老的唯一原因——细胞还承受着其他一些我们尚不太了解的压力——但端粒短是人体细胞变老的主要原因之一。
We’ve devoted most of our careers to studying telomeres, and one extraordinary discovery from our labs is that telomeres can actually lengthen.
我们已经把职业生涯的大部分时间投入到端粒研究中，而我们实验室的一项非凡发现是：端粒其实能够变长。
Scientists have learned that several thought patterns appear to be unhealthy for telomeres, and one of them is cynical hostility.
科学家们已经了解到，有几种思维模式似乎不利于端粒健康，其中之一就是愤世嫉俗式敌意。
Cynical hostility is defined by high anger and frequent thoughts that other people cannot be trusted.
愤世嫉俗式敌意的特征是怒气重，并且常常认为别人不可信任。
Someone with hostility doesn’t just think, “I hate to stand in long lines”; they think, “Others deliberately sped up and beat me to my rightful position in the line!”—and then get violently agitated.
怀有敌意的人不只是会想“我讨厌排长队”，而是会想“别人故意加快速度，抢在我前面占了队伍里本该属于我的位置！”——然后就变得极度激动。
People who score high on measures of cynical hostility tend to get more heart disease and metabolic disease and often die at younger ages.
在愤世嫉俗式敌意测评中得分高的人，往往更容易患心脏病和代谢疾病，而且常常更早离世。
They also have shorter telomeres.
他们的端粒也更短。
In a study of British civil servants, men who scored high on measures of cynical hostility had shorter telomeres than men whose hostility scores were low.
在一项针对英国公务员的研究中，愤世嫉俗式敌意测评得分高的男性，端粒比敌意得分低的男性更短。
The most hostile men were 30% more likely to have short telomeres.
敌意最强的男性，端粒短的可能性要高出30%。
What this means: aging is a dynamic process that could possibly be accelerated or slowed—and, in some aspects, even reversed.
这意味着：衰老是一个动态过程，有可能加快或减缓——而且在某些方面甚至可能逆转。
To an extent, it has surprised us and the rest of the scientific community that telomeres do not simply carry out the commands issued by your genetic code.
端粒并不只是执行你的遗传密码发出的指令，这在一定程度上让我们和科学界的其他人都感到意外。
Your telomeres are listening to you.
你的端粒在倾听你。
The foods you eat, your response to challenges, the amount of exercise you get, and many other factors appear to influence your telomeres and can prevent premature aging at the cellular level.
你吃的食物、对挑战的反应、运动量以及许多其他因素，似乎都会影响你的端粒，而且能在细胞层面防止过早衰老。
One of the keys to enjoying good health is simply doing your part to foster healthy cell renewal.
保持身体健康的关键之一，其实就是尽好自己的一份力，促进细胞的健康更新。